<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenNSA – CLI User Guide</title>
    <link>https://NORDUnet.github.io/opennsa/docs/usage-guide/cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CLI User Guide on OpenNSA</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="https://NORDUnet.github.io/opennsa/docs/usage-guide/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: User Guide</title>
      <link>https://NORDUnet.github.io/opennsa/docs/usage-guide/cli/onsa_cli/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://NORDUnet.github.io/opennsa/docs/usage-guide/cli/onsa_cli/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;A short primer on the onsa command line tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: There are still bugs and unfinished functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The onsa command line tools allows the creation of connections and basic
lifecycle management, along with query functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cannot wait to get started, you can list the command options with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ onsa --help
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command line tool requires a command (e.g., reserve or provision), and a
set of options, in order to carry out a command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Defaults file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often there will be a number of options, which will be the same or almost the
same with every invocation, e.g., location of topology files, WSDL directory,
identity of the client and so forth. To save time, the CLI will read on default
options from a file, typically ~/.opennsa-cli, but it is possible to specify an
alternate location using the -f (&amp;ndash;defaults-file) option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of a &lt;code&gt;.opennsa-cli&lt;/code&gt; defaults file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;bandwidth=200
host=localhost
port=7080
starttime=+20
endtime=+260

nsa=aruba,aruba.net:2013:nsa,http://localhost:4080/NSI/services/CS2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The host and port options, will be used in setting up the callback URL. They
will default to the value provided by &amp;ldquo;socket.getfqdn()&amp;rdquo; and 7080.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starttime and endtime can be set to xsd datetime value, but can also be
assigned a +X value, with X being the number of seconds into the future. This
makes it easy to always get some usefull values when testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nsa entry, allow a shorthand for specifying nsa id and service url. With
the above example, one can use
&amp;ldquo;-p aruba&amp;rdquo;
instead
&amp;ldquo;-p aruba.net:2013:nsa -u http://localhost:4080/NSI/services/CS2&amp;rdquo;
This makes the command line tool a lot nicer to use. There can be multiple
nsa shorthand entries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If an option is specified both on the command line and in the defaults file,
the command line value will be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is possible to set all options which can be set on the command line in the
defaults file, with the exception of the command to perform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using the tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a default options file created, a connection can be created like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ ./onsa reserve --source northernlight.ets:ps --dest northernlight.ets:ams -p northernlight.ets
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A connection id and global id is assigned automatically but can also be
assigned using the -c and -g options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To provision the connection:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./onsa provision -p northernlight.ets -c &amp;lt;connection-id&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly with release and terminate, querysummary, and querydetails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;STP Syntax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STP without VLAN (full port - rarely used)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;northernlight.ets:ps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STP with VLAN 23, this is the typical one to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;northernlight.ets:ps?vlan=23&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also MPLS (you should know what you are doing wrt. labels)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;northernlight.ets:ps?mpls=123:456&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
